<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Shoddy Merchandise &#8211; Pushing Back</title>
	<atom:link href="/archives/category/shoddy-merchandise/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 21:08:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Hyundai Updates Manual</title>
		<link>/archives/243</link>
					<comments>/archives/243#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Todd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 21:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Shoddy Merchandise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a guest post. We bought a new 2019 Hyundai Elantra. Initially everything seemed fine. But it wasn’t long before we noticed the average MPG was resetting every morning and after refueling. Further, there was no multimedia manual; so, we weren’t sure if there were other electronics issues. After talking to the dealer, they &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/archives/243"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Hyundai Updates Manual</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This is a guest post.<br></p>



<p>We bought a new 2019 Hyundai Elantra. Initially everything seemed fine. But it wasn’t long before we noticed the average MPG was resetting every morning and after refueling. Further, there was no multimedia manual; so, we weren’t sure if there were other electronics issues.<br></p>



<p>After talking to the dealer, they agreed to have someone look at the car but refused to give us the multimedia manual. We met with the dealer’s service representative, and he said he would investigate. Eventually he got back to us and insisted that despite what the owner’s manual stated, the car is suppose to automatically reset the average MPG as our car was doing, and that they would not be repairing the vehicle. Also, still no multimedia manual.<br></p>



<p>So we wrote a letter to the credit card company about the defective product which was purchased partially with credit. The credit card company reversed the $3000 charge. We might have been satisfied with this solution; however, the dealer was able to convince the credit card company to reapply the charge.<br></p>



<p>Then we contacted the EPA. After all, the dealer and manufacturer asserted the car was intentionally hiding the average gas mileage from us; so clearly they don’t want anyone to easily ascertain what the true gas mileage is. It took a bit of cajoling, but a guy from the EPA did go and contact the manufacturer. The manufacturer eventually fed the EPA guy some tale about how there were field complaints that the vehicles were providing inaccurate average gas mileage; thus, to address that problem,&nbsp; they opted to automatically reset the average MPG after four hours off key.  Not sure how that solved the inaccuracy problem, but this explanation seems to have satisfied the EPA’s concerns for the moment. But this is where things get really bizarre.<br></p>



<p>The owner’s manual provided at sale doesn’t actually say anything about the average MPG automatically resetting; yet the manufacturer just told the EPA that they are indeed intentionally resetting it in model year 2019 Hyundais. So the manufacturer printed us a custom owner’s manual, an exact replica of the original with the same binding and size, but with one small change that says the average MPG is supposed to reset when off key for four hours. It still does not reflect what the car actually does, but I guess it’s good enough for Hyundai work.&nbsp; They then tried to get us to return the old manual. And finally, they manage to give us the multimedia manual.<br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" width="1024" height="768" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0022-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-245" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0022-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0022-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/11/IMG_0022-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Apparently, when you sell a defective product under warranty, all you have to do is print a new manual that states the defect is a feature. Problem solved! But seriously, why the cover-up? Why invest so much effort to document your own misdeeds and risk the ire of the government or a lawsuit? Wouldn’t it have been so much easier and less likely to bring attention to the problem if they had simply repaired or exchanged the vehicle for another? So now here is the idiocy documented on the internet.<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/archives/243/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A place to sleep (continued)</title>
		<link>/archives/153</link>
					<comments>/archives/153#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Todd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 20:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Shoddy Merchandise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[See last post. So the service guy came out. He was able to lower the bed portion of the sofa an inch, which was as far down as it would go. Then he found some cylindrical legs, which were slightly shorter, that look like they belonged to a different type of furniture. After making those &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/archives/153"> <span class="screen-reader-text">A place to sleep (continued)</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>See <a href="?p=142" title="last post">last post</a>.</p>
<p>So the service guy came out.  He was able to lower the bed portion of the sofa an inch, which was as far down as it would go.  Then he found some cylindrical legs, which were slightly shorter, that look like they belonged to a different type of furniture.  After making those changes, the bed is only elevated slightly.  We have decided it&#8217;s good enough.  What boggles my mind is that even with the bed screwed in as low as it can possibly go, it&#8217;s still clearly not right.  The only possibilities I can think of are either (1) they put the wrong model bed into the sofa, or (2) the sofa has a fundamental design flaw, and they&#8217;ve just decided to sell it that way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/archives/153/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A place to sleep (continued)</title>
		<link>/archives/142</link>
					<comments>/archives/142#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Todd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 23:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Caveat Emptor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shoddy Merchandise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[See last post. VCF set a time. They called the day before, but it turned out they wouldn&#8217;t go to my address. After hanging up, I did some research and found out that there was another store close by. I had to make numerous calls to two different stores. Every VCF seems to have a &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/archives/142"> <span class="screen-reader-text">A place to sleep (continued)</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="?p=139" title="Last post">See last post.</a></p>
<p>VCF set a time.  They called the day before, but it turned out they wouldn&#8217;t go to my address.  After hanging up, I did some research and found out that there was another store close by.  I had to make numerous calls to two different stores.  Every VCF seems to have a different system for handling calls.  Store 59 has a particularly obnoxious call waiting sound.  It&#8217;s a loud beep every few seconds.  I guess they really don&#8217;t want your call.</p>
<p>Eventually, I thought that they were going to call back to set a new time, but after calling a couple of times, I thought maybe they were avoiding me instead.  So that evening, I sent a nasty email through their website.  This may have been a little premature.</p>
<blockquote><p>
Hello, I waited a week and a half to have a service person sent out to fix my new sofa.  Then I was told store 59 doesn&#8217;t go to [removed].  After several more phone calls, I found out that store 74 does service [removed].  I&#8217;ve called twice and was supposed to receive a return call.</p>
<p>Please take a look at the wonderful quality of this Value City Furniture product!  I was not expecting luxury for under $1000, but is it too much to ask that it at least be functional?  These photos go up on my blog next week.</p>
<p>In the mean time, I spent a lot of money on this nearly functional sofa bed, and I plan to use it.  It&#8217;s really wobbly though; I hope I don&#8217;t get hurt.  I don&#8217;t suppose you know what jury awards for product liability torts go for these days?  It&#8217;s probably a little more than the three dollars in gas it will take to send the service tech out here.  Anyhow, give me a call.
</p></blockquote>
<p>I provided links to the following images.<br />
<a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/bed1.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/bed1-300x224.jpg" alt="" title="bed1" width="300" height="224" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-143" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/bed1-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/bed1-1024x764.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><br />
<a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/bed2.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/bed2-300x224.jpg" alt="" title="bed2" width="300" height="224" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-147" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/bed2-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2012/07/bed2-1024x764.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>I called again the next morning and they finally agreed to send a service technician.  There was also some whining about how they weren&#8217;t really supposed to do this since I picked the sofa up myself rather than paying for the delivery fee.  Later in the day, someone called about the email I had sent.  I told him store 74 had agreed to send someone out; he sounded relieved.  Now we&#8217;ll find out if they can actually fix the problem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/archives/142/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A place to sleep</title>
		<link>/archives/139</link>
					<comments>/archives/139#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Todd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 01:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Caveat Emptor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shoddy Merchandise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My girlfriend followed me to Maryland. She hired MBM Moving Systems to move her stuff. For the most part, everything went fine. But her sofa showed up with oil stains on it. She didn&#8217;t pay for an extended insurance policy, so her damages were limited to 60 cents per pound, or $180 for the sofa. &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/archives/139"> <span class="screen-reader-text">A place to sleep</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My girlfriend followed me to Maryland.  She hired MBM Moving Systems to move her stuff.  For the most part, everything went fine.  But her sofa showed up with oil stains on it.  She didn&#8217;t pay for an extended insurance policy, so her damages were limited to 60 cents per pound, or $180 for the sofa.  This covered slightly more than the cost of having the stains removed.</p>
<p>Unfortunately removing oil stains from fabric is really hard, and the company she hired to do it wasn&#8217;t very successful.  We decided to flip the cushions over and live with the remaining stains.  They weren&#8217;t that noticeable.  But then we got a big surprise.  The bed in the sofa was wrecked beyond repair.  I have never even been able to figure out how it was damaged so badly.  It must have taken some immense force, like say dropping it a story, yet somehow the exterior of the sofa was not damaged.  In any case she was screwed.</p>
<p>But it gets better.  In order to get the $180 for a sofa that cost around five times as much, they made her sign a document that said they had no further obligations and that she would not report them to any reporting agencies such as the BBB.  And she had to get it notarized.  I doubt that such a document would hold up in court if it was challenged, but they still withheld her money until it was signed and notarized.</p>
<p>I needed a cheap sofa for my house.  So I bought her a new sofa bed, and took her still-functional-as-a-sofa sofa bed.  Value City Furniture (VCF) has lower end furniture that you can get at good prices.  We found a sofa bed that I thought was comparable to, but maybe not quite as nice, as what she had, and it was on sale for $500.  When we picked it up, I made sure it was intact and that it included the bed.  It was possible to buy the same sofa without the bed for $100 less, so I need to make sure they didn&#8217;t screw it up.  Everything looked good.</p>
<p>And yet it wasn&#8217;t.  After we set it up and attached the feet, I found out that the top of the bed was three to four inches higher than the bottom of the bed.  Basically, it was unusable.  I don&#8217;t understand how such a thing ever could have even left the factory.  It would have take 10 seconds to pull it out and look at it and see that it was not fit for sale.</p>
<p>By now I&#8217;m getting upset.  She spent around $900 for a sofa that only lasted a few years.  Then she spent another $100 on an air mattress to replace the bed.  I invested another $500, and we still don&#8217;t have a working sofa bed, never mind the time we&#8217;ve invested.  I drove all the way back to the store to verify the demo model they had shown us did in fact have a bed that was level with the ground.  I was told to have the service department have a service technician come out and take a look.</p>
<p>More to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/archives/139/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
