<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Regulatory Agencies &#8211; Pushing Back</title>
	<atom:link href="/archives/category/regulatory-agencies/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 16:01:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Maryland Attorney General Not Helpful</title>
		<link>/archives/202</link>
					<comments>/archives/202#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Todd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 20:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Regulatory Agencies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I went to the Maryland Attorney General website a while back and went through the whole process of filling out the rather lengthy consumer complaint form on the quality of C&#8217;s loans. The site requires you to send a paper copy to the Attorney General&#8217;s office. So I prepared and printed all the paperwork yet &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/archives/202"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Maryland Attorney General Not Helpful</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I went to the Maryland Attorney General website a while back and went through the whole process of filling out the rather lengthy consumer complaint form on the quality of C&#8217;s loans.  The site requires you to send a paper copy to the Attorney General&#8217;s office.  So I prepared and printed all the paperwork yet again.  Eventually I was notified that this was not the Attorney General&#8217;s problem.  Supposedly the matter was forwarded to the CFPB, but I never heard of it again.  Even so, it would have just been forwarded to the NCUA, where it would promptly disappear into the void.  Hopeless&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/archives/202/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NCUA Does Not Like Me</title>
		<link>/archives/199</link>
					<comments>/archives/199#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Todd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 20:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Regulatory Agencies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The NCUA seems to be going out of its way to be unhelpful to me. I pay the taxes that fund its employees salaries; it ignores me. Its employees do not respond to my emails unless it&#8217;s forwarded on by the CFPB. They always find a way to interpret the law in such a way &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/archives/199"> <span class="screen-reader-text">NCUA Does Not Like Me</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The NCUA seems to be going out of its way to be unhelpful to me.  I pay the taxes that fund its employees salaries; it ignores me.  Its employees do not respond to my emails unless it&#8217;s forwarded on by the CFPB.  They always find a way to interpret the law in such a way that they don&#8217;t actually have to do any work.  I wanted to find out if they were ignoring or discriminating against me, so I created an email account under a Hispanic name.  I emailed an inarticulate complaint in broken English, and it took a week, but they responded by opening a case number and asking for more information.  So I feel justified when I say they really don&#8217;t like me.</p>
<p>The Credit Union (C from here on) banned me from using its services.  Just to be a thorn in its side, I sent a complaint to the CFPB.  I stated that Section 1764 of the <a href="http://www.ncua.gov/Legal/Documents/fcu_act.pdf" title="Federal Credit Union Act">Federal Credit Union Act</a> gives me the right to be heard prior to expulsion by a formal vote.  The CFPB forwarded my complaint to the NCUA.  It emailed the following response and then immediately closed the ticket so that I had no way of responding.  The respondent did not ask any questions about the situation or attempt to be of any help.</p>
<blockquote><p>As a member of a Federal Credit Union, the Federal Credit Union Act (FCU Act), grants all members’ two basic rights: the right to maintain a share account and the right to vote at annual meetings. 12 U.S.C. §§1759, 1769. However, nothing in the FCU Act or NCUA’s Rules and Regulations precludes a FCU from restricting the availability of certain services provided there is a rational basis for such action. See Legal Opinion Letter 08-0431 (available at www.ncua.gov). The credit union is within their right to limit services to some members.</p></blockquote>
<p>The <a href="http://www.ncua.gov/Legal/Pages/OL2008-0431.aspx" title="Legal Opinion">Legal Opinion</a> referenced here states that there needed to be some loss by C.  And further, C would need to provide me with a formal policy of suspension of services.  I don&#8217;t know whether such a policy exists, but I was not offered one or told where it could be found.  Further, at the time I discovered C had banned me, I don&#8217;t believe I had actually cost C a single penny.</p>
<p>The NCUA would not respond to me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/archives/199/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
